New Monmouth Presbyterian Church records WLU.Coll.0168
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
New Monmouth Presbyterian Church records
1858-1984
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
New Monmouth Presbyterian Church (Lexington, Va.)
WLU.Coll.0168
14 Box
Existence and Location of Copies
Aspects of this collection have been microfilmed.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes deacons' minutes, sunday school records, the church register, cemetery records, congregational meeting minutes, and financial records of New Monmouth Presbyterian Church. Also includes some issues of the New Monmouth News/Newsletter, August 1979 - December 1981, March 1984, December 1987, May 2001, no date.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research use.
Records; Cemeteries; Scrapbooks; Account books; Church societies; Church history; Church officers
- Cemetery records, 1905-1974? (Box 1)
- Sunday School records and Church register (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Sunday School records, 1921-1931, and Church Register, 1771-1959
- Deacons' minute book, 1895-1925, 1934-1981 (Box 3)
- Financial records, 1931-1974 (Box 4)
- Yearbooks and scrapbooks (Box 5)
  Yearbooks, 1960-1962, and scrapbooks, 1776-1822
- Congregational meeting minutes, pew rents, scrapbooks, and history of the church (Box 6)
  Congregational meeting minutes 1851-1916; pew rents; scrapbooks 1980-1981, 1982-1984; history of the church 1912
- Miscellaneous A-N (Box 7A)
- Miscellaneous O-Z (Box 7B)
- Women of the Church Minutes, 1922-1958 (Box 8)
- Women of the Church Executive Board minutes, Secretary's books, Treasurer's books (Box 9)
  Women of the Church Executive Board minutes 1951-1956, Secretary's books 1951-1956, Treasurer's books 1914-1955
- Account books, 1879-1891, 1891-1895, 1912-1914 (Box 10)
- Session minutes, 1892-1920, 1935-1953 (Box 11)
- Session minutes and Congregational meeting minutes, 1953-1965, 1965-1970, 1970-1977 (Box 12)
- Receipts and expenses, Foreign mission receipts, Pastor's salary account, LH and FMA minutes, Circle No. 8 minutes, WA minutes, letter (Box 13)
  Receipts and expenses 1911-1927; Foreign mission receipts1906-1931; Pastor's salary account 1907-1912, 1921-1924; LH and FMA minutes 1913-1918; Circle No. 8 minutes 1927-1933; WA minutes 1923-1924; letter 1907
- Session minutes, sessional record of KCBPC, and session book of the Chesnut Grove Presbyterian Church (Box 14)
  Session minutes 1848-1858, 1858-1892, 1920-1935; sessional record of KCBPC 1903-1929; session book of the Chesnut Grove Presbyterian Church 1910-1921